

Edward John Parkinson

- Southampton
- +44 7780 114795
- edward.parkinson@pm.me
- in linkedin.com/in/edward-parkinson
- github.com/saultyevil
- edwardparkinson.co.uk

PROFILE

I am a PhD student at the University of Southampton, simulating the light emitted when a star is ripped apart by a black hole, in something known as a Tidal Disruption Event. I am part of the Next Generational Computational Modelling Centre for Doctoral Training (NGCM-CDT) based at the University of Southampton, where I trained in modern computational techniques and numerical modelling. I completed my masters in physics with astrophysics at the University of Kent where I graduated first class with honours in 2016, specialising in fluid dynamic simulations of jetted material ejected from galaxies. During my PhD, I have had the opportunity to build my computational, HPC and communication skills, attending international workshops and conferences to share my work with and learn from the community. I worked with vast quantities of synthetic and real world data, applying a modern toolkit of data analysis techniques, statistical modelling, Python/R frameworks and numerical techniques to confront theory with observations, producing novel and state-of-the-art research. I have been the principle investigator for multiple collaborative and individual research projects and a key team member in cross-disciplinary collaborations and projects.

EMPLOYMENT

2016 - 2017

Customer relation manager

Yorkshire Water Business Services, Bradford

- Account manager for key customer businesses
- · Solved complex billing queries and meter readings

2016 – 2016 Data entry clerk

Loop Customer Management, Bradford

 Temporary position, transitioned into permanent role with Yorkshire Water Business Services

EDUCATION

2017 - current

iPhD: next generation computational modelling

School of Physics and Astronomy, University of Southampton

- PhD thesis: Shining lights, even in death: modelling the emission from Tidal Disruption Events
- Year 1: integrated master; statistics, computational techniques and programming/dev skills with a strong focus on state-of-the-art high performance computing and cross-disciplinary communication
- Year 2 4: PhD research in computational astrophysics; maintained and developed (legacy) Monte Carlo code PYTHON

2012 - 2016 MPhys: physics with astrophysics

School of Physical Sciences, University of Kent

- · Awarded first class with honours
- Bachelors dissertation: Measuring the proper motion of nearby stars and brown dwarfs
- Masters thesis: Adiabatic hydrodynamic simulations of two-dimensional inviscid extragalatic jets

SKILLS

Core skills

Data analysis and statistical/numerical modelling

- · Applied modern statistical and numerical modelling techniques to my research
- Experience with working with big data sets
- Published state-of-the-art research using modern computational techniques
- · Streamlined development work-flow for storage, analysis and presentation of research data

Software development

- · Data structure and algorithm design
- Version control
- Unit and regression testing
- Cross-platform design

Project management

- Principle investigator of multiple collaborative and independent research projects
- Guided MSc student projects

Visualisation

- Experienced with multiple modern visualisation tools
- Proficient in creating publication grade figures using, e.g. matplotlib

Communication

- · Strong technical writing style
- Author on multiple journal articles
- · Experienced presenter for expert and non-expert audiences
- Demonstrator for introduction to Python and version control courses

Collaboration

· Invaluable member of multiple international and national collaborations

Programming languages

C; Python; Fortran; LATEX; R; Rust; SQL

Software

Git; Travis; NumPy; SciPy; Pandas; CUDA; MPI; OpenMP; pytest; TensorFlow; Imfit; Django; Jekyll; Microsoft Office; Unix; Windows; macOS

PROJECTS

pypython

A fully featured Python package designed to analyse and visualise the output from the radiative transfer program PYTHON and also contains a family of functions useful in scientific computation

https://github.com/saultyevil/pypython

transfer

Monte Carlo radiative Example programs of a simple Monte Carlo radiative transfer problem, written in multiple programming styles and languages

https://github.com/saultyevil/mcrt

atomix

A bespoke terminal based tool, designed for browsing the atomic data files in scientific software

https://github.com/saultyevil/atomix

website

A personal webpage and portfolio, developed using Jekyll. https://github.com/saultyevil/saultyevil.github.io

adminbot

A Discord bot, written using discordpy, which uses Markov Chains to generate sentences and learns how to communicate from repeated user interaction https://github.com/saultyevil/adminbot

PUBLICATIONS

2021 Parkinson et al., Optical line spectra of tidal disruption events from reprocessing in optically thick outflows, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, submitted

2020 Parkinson et al., Accretion disc winds in tidal disruption events: ultraviolet spectral lines as orientation indicators, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 494, Issue 4, June 2020, Pages 4914-4929